Five of characters.
五万
There's something fishy between you two.
你们两个有猫腻的
-We're just in sync. -Hurry.
默契 快点
I'm in such good luck today.
我今儿手气可好啊
Watch it.
来
Pung!
碰
-Good for you. -I just won.
不错哦 和咯
And you won big.
你和大牌
-You’re so lucky. -Take a bite.
你这运气也太好了吧 来一个
Can't believe you pulled it off.
这种牌也能和
You're back?
回来了
Leave him be.
不管他
Pay up!
拿钱呐
Chengye, you're back.
小业回来了
Your mom and the others already ate.
你妈他们都已经吃过了啊
I saved some food for you.
我这边给你留了饭
Come eat it in a bit.
等一下过来吃啊
Auntie.
阿姨
That thing...
那个
Is it a gift from him again?
又是他送的
Finally, a big weight's off my mind.
总算是完成心中一件大事
Ms. Lin,
小林老师
you're not letting things take their own course now?
这时候不讲究顺其自然了
If I keep on that track,
再顺其自然下去
I'll be stuck in a rut and achieve nothing.
我就要原地踏步碌碌无为了
You took the words right out of my mouth.
这倒是说出了我的心声
What do you mean, Coach Wang?
什么意思啊王教练
We're back on good terms now, aren't we?
所以我们现在算是和好了吧
Yes, merely.
勉强算是吧
We have merely
勉强算是
restored our partnership
修复了以利益维系的
maintained by mutual interests.
合作伙伴关系
Is that all?
只有这么多
What else do you want?
那你还想咋滴啊
I...
我
There's a flower shop ahead.
前面有间花店
I'm going there to buy fertilizer.
我去买点化肥
♪ Every night ♪
我
I know. I know.
我知道 我知道
Do you dare to hit me?
你敢打我吗
-Coach, Ms. Lin. -Ms. Lin.
教练 小林老师 小林老师
We just heard from the organizing committee
我们刚收到组委会通知
that our next opponent has been changed to Yongchuan Hengjiu.
下一场的比赛对手换成永川恒久
Yongchuan Hengjiu?
永川恒久
Are you kidding me?
开什么国际玩笑
Weren't we supposed to play Xinpeng?
不是说好踢鑫鹏吗
The students of Xinpeng were informed on a short notice
鑫鹏的同学们被临时通知
of attending an important local event that overlaps
要去参加市里一个很重要的活动
in schedule with the match.
和比赛撞期了
As if we weren't already on thin ice.
这是嫌我们死得不够快
What was that gibberish?
你说什么话呢
Ms. Lin,
小林老师
they can't just change our opponent, can they?
这不能说换就换吧
In the group round-robin,
小组循环赛里
it's reasonable and compliant with the rules to adjust the sequence
队伍因不可抗力调换比赛顺序
of group matches.
合理合规
But that doesn't mean they had to replace
那也不能把我们对手
our original opponent with Yongchuan Hengjiu.
换成永川恒久吧
They scored nine goals in their previous match.
上一场他们灌了人家九个球
Nine goals.
九个
Their list of players includes
他们的大名单里
three National Youth Team members.
有三个国青队成员
One of them is Fang Sulun,
其中方苏伦
who did a bicycle kick in the box in an earlier match
在上次对战日本青年队时
against the Japanese Youth League,
在禁区一个倒挂金钩
showcasing superb skills.
技术高超
Not to mention Qin Qiechu.
秦且初就更不用提了
Everyone on the online forum
论坛上都说
says he's being groomed
他被当作国家队
as a key reserve player for the national team.
后备主力成员培养
Wait.
不是
Do you have to throw a wet blanket
你非得在这个时候
on everyone at a time like this?
泼大家一盆冷水是吧
I'm just stating the facts.
我说的都是事实
Fragility is not to be denied.
菜就要认
Enough, the two of you.
你俩行了
Coach.
教练
What's your opinion?
你觉得呢
What opinion can I have?
我觉得什么呀
You all did a good job on the analysis.
大家分析得挺好的呀
I was not asking you about that.
不是让您说这个
I meant our chances of defeating Yongchuan Hengjiu.
是我们踢永川恒久的胜算
The chances are slim,
胜算很小
but there is still hope.
但有希望
I think you should just eat and sleep well,
我觉得好好吃饭好好睡觉
and get onto the field with a calm mind.
平常心上场
Go home and rest early.
早点回去休息吧
Conserve your energy.
保存体力
Try your best in tomorrow's match.
明天好好比赛
Okay.
好
Can't believe we'll play Hengjiu.
居然踢恒久
This is so stressful.
压力好大
Bye bye.
拜拜拜拜
Just take the coach's advice.
听教练的
Eat and drink as usual.
该吃吃该喝喝啊
I probably won't be able to sleep tonight.
我今晚怕是睡不着咯
You make it sound like you could do it.
说得好像你能做得到一样
Off you go. We'll walk together next time.
你走吧 下次咱再一块走
Okay, I'm leaving then.
行 那我先走了
-Bye. -I'm leaving too. Bye.
拜拜 走了 拜拜 拜拜
-Bye bye.
拜拜 拜拜 拜拜
Goodbye, Ms. Lin.
老师再见
-Bye-bye.
拜拜 拜拜
Goodbye, Coach.
再见教练
Fu, shall we?
走啊老付
Sure.
走
Anything wrong?
咋了
Did you lose anything?
丢东西了
I can't find my keychain.
我钥匙扣找不见了
The one with that utterly ugly jersey, right?
就是那件特丑的球衣是吧
If it's gone, just let it be.
好了丢就丢了
That stuff's tacky after all, right?
那么土 对吧
Fu Xinshu!
付新书
-Fu Xinshu, look what time it is now. -No, I must find it.
付新书你看看几点了
I'll buy you a new one tomorrow.
我明天再给你买一个
Let's go grab a bite first.
你先陪我去吃宵夜
Come on. Let's go.
走了走了走了
Hey, kids.
来 小朋友们
Let's go watch cartoons.
我们去看动画片啦
Come on, kids.
来 小朋友
Kids, time to watch cartoons.
小朋友们我们去看动画片啦
Hey, kiddo?
小朋友
Everyone's here, right?
都集合好了吧
Yiling, come on.
还有小依玲 走吧
Why didn't you go watch cartoons with the others?
你怎么不和大家一起去看影片啊
I don't know them.
我不认识他们
Don't you want to get to know them?
那你不想认识他们吗
I've seen you staying
我已经看你好几次
in your ward alone several times.
一个人待在病房里了
Where are your parents?
你爸妈呢
They didn't come see me.
他们都没来
Do you play football?
那你会踢球吗
I just joined the school team this semester.
我这学期刚加入了校队
Let's go play football together.
我们一起去踢球吧
But we're in a hospital now.
可是这里是医院
It doesn't matter.
没关系
I have a big secret hideout.
我有个很大的秘密基地
Come with me.
走了
Don't keep yourself in the ward all the time.
不要整天待在病房里嘛
Basking in the sun outside
出去多晒晒太阳
more often will help you recover faster.
病也会好得快一些
My name is Fu Xinshu.
我叫付新书
What's yours?
你叫什么名字
My dad doesn't like me.
我爸爸不喜欢我
And I hate being his son.
我也不想做他儿子
So I don't have a name.
所以我没有名字
I'll call you Bed No. 4 then.
那我就叫你四号床吧
Let's go play football, Bed No. 4.
四号床去踢球
Quick!
快点 快点 快点
I'll go get the ball.
我先去拿球
Bed No. 4,
四号床
today, I'll teach you how to
我今天教你怎么样
precisely get hold of the ball.
才能精准地踢到球
Okay.
好
Bed No. 4.
四号床
You stay right here.
你就在这
You're still in recovery.
你病还没好
Do be careful.
你慢点啊
Got it.
好
Very good.
很好
Fu Xinshu, this is no fun at all.
付新书你这样踢太没劲了
Let's both take a few steps back.
咱们往后点
You should kick harder.
你用力大一点
Over here.
在这里在这里
Catch it.
接着
Now, pass it to me.
来 传
Okay.
好
Catch this one. Here it goes!
接好了 来
Come on, pass it over!
来传这
There it goes.
给
Okay!
好
P-Pass the ball to me.
给我传 传传球
Pass it now!
传
♪ As my badge of honor ♪
传 传
You've got this! Shoot!
加油 射门
Bed No. 4.
四号床
You'll be discharged soon, right?
你马上就要出院了对吧
Fu Xinshu, thanks for teaching me how to play football.
付新书 谢谢你教我踢足球
It looks cute.
这个挺可爱的
I'll hang it on my backpack.
我要挂在我书包上
Then you must never take it off.
那你永远也不许取下来
Bed No. 4,
四号床
you're about to leave the hospital,
你都要出院了
yet I still don't know your name.
但我还不知道你的名字呢
Well, then meet me next week
那等下个礼拜
on my birthday at that fried chicken place.
我过生日约在炸鸡店
I'll tell you when you get there.
你一来我就告诉你
Okay. I'll definitely be there.
好 我一定会去的
Great.
好
Come on.
来
-Pinky swear.
拉钩上吊
-No backsies.
一百年不许变
I promised a classmate
我约了同学
to spend my birthday with him.
我要跟同学一起过生日
No, you can't go.
不行
You have to spend this birthday
这个生日你必须和
with your grandparents.
爷爷奶奶一起过
We are moving to Yongchuan soon.
马上我们就搬去永川了
Why are we moving?
为什么搬走
To start a new company— at least it appears so.
表面上是开新公司
But in fact,
实际上
it's just to make it easier
还不是方便你爸
for your dad to meet with his side piece.
跟那个小狐狸精见面
Hu Yongping!
胡永平
Why did you have to speak nonsense when our son's around?
当着孩子面你胡说八道什么呀
What did I do wrong?
我怎么了啊
Spare me that crap.
你少跟我扯那些没用的
You want to dump me, huh?
你还想把我甩了
I'm telling you, not a chance.
告诉你门都没有
Shut that filthy mouth of yours!
闭上你的臭嘴吧
I want to go to...
我要去
You shut it too!
你也闭嘴
Listen up, sign the papers
我告诉你
if you want a divorce.
想离就签字
Why can't I speak?
我为什么闭嘴
Retain what little shame you have.
你别不要脸
-You may have it, but I still do! -I'm not going to divorce you.
你不要脸
-Chengye! -You stay put!
小业 你坐在这
Chengye!
小业
Where are you going?
干什么去
Come back here, Chengye!
回来 小业
Chengye!
小业
Chengye, come back!
小业回来
Never ever come back if you dare run away!
你要是敢跑就永远别回来
You should've watched out.
小心啊
Little boy,
小朋友
are you okay?
小朋友你没事吧
I'm fine.
没事
Thank God I'm not late.
还好没迟到
Come on, get some fries.
来来来吃薯条吃薯条
What a spread.
好多
Help yourself to whatever you like.
喜欢吃什么拿
Has he forgotten our pact?
他忘记了吗
How is it? Is it good?
怎么样 好不好吃
Yes.
好吃
Go ask that boy.
去问一下
Hey, little one,
弟弟
can we swap seats with you?
我们可以和你交换一下位置吗
Sure.
可以 谢谢
Here comes the birthday cake!
生日蛋糕 来喽
Happy birthday!
生日快乐
Happy birthday to you.
祝你生日快乐
Bed No. 4, you're about to leave the hospital,
四号床你都要出院了
yet I still don't know your name.
但我还不知道你的名字呢
Well, then meet me next week
那等下个礼拜
on my birthday at that fried chicken place.
我过生日约在炸鸡店
I'll tell you when you get there.
你一来我就告诉你
Okay, I will definitely be there.
好我一定会去的
-Pinky swear. No backsies.
拉钩上吊一百年不许变
Hello, it's our child's birthday today.
来 今天我们小朋友过生日
We'd like to offer you a cup of ice cream.
跟你们分享一个冰淇淋
Hey, little one,
弟弟
a free cup of ice cream for you.
跟你分享一下冰淇淋
-Thank you. -Here you are, a spoon.
谢谢 来还有勺子
It's our child's birthday.
我们小朋友过生日
-We'd like to share the joy with you. -Thanks.
跟你们分享一下 谢谢
Look, here's ice cream.
来还有冰淇淋哦
Come on.
来
-Here you are. -You got one yet?
来 拿了吗
Are you having fun?
开不开心
A spoon for you.
勺子
Little boy, you've been sitting here alone the entire day.
小朋友你一个人坐在这一整天了
Where are your parents?
你爸爸妈妈呢
We're closing the place.
我们要打烊了哦
Never ever come back if you dare run away!
你要是敢跑就永远别回来
Now you get it.
你现在知道了
You're nothing
离开文家
when you're out of the Wen family.
你什么都不是
Finish it and go home.
吃完回家
If you're not eating it, put it away and get up!
不吃收起来站起来
Wen Chengye, how come you're still here?
文成业你还没走啊
Why did you come back?
你怎么回来了
Don't get me started.
别提了
I lost something really important.
我丢了一个很重要的东西
I must find it back.
必须要把它给找出来
So you found it?
是你捡到的
Thank you.
谢谢你啊
Is it very important to you?
这东西对你很重要吗
I made someone a promise
我答应别人了
that I'd never take it off.
不会把它取下来
Why the laugh?
笑什么
It really is of great importance to me.
它对我来说就是很重要嘛
Is that so?
是吗
If it truly meant so much to you,
真那么重要的话
how could you not recognize me?
你认不出我
Bed No. 4...
四号床
You are Bed No. 4?
你是四号床
Drop the act.
少来
Don't pretend like you still remember me.
别装作一副还没忘的样子
I do remember you.
我没忘啊
How could I have forgotten? I...
我怎么可能忘 我
I've always wanted to find you
我一直都想再找到你
and play football with you again.
再和你一起踢球
You were my very first best friend.
你是我第一个最好的朋友
Then why didn't you come meet me?
那你为什么没来
We made a pinky promise
我们拉钩
that you'd celebrate my birthday with me.
说好你来陪我过生日
I waited for you for a whole day.
我等了你一天
Why?
为什么
Why on earth didn't you show up?
到底是为什么
I'll ask you one last time.
我最后问你一遍
Why?
为什么
I don't want to say it.
我不想说
Think whatever you want.
随便你怎么想
Fu!
老付
Wen Chengye, what's wrong with you?
文成业 你犯什么病
-You fancy a beating or what? -Qin Ao!
我给你脸了是吧 秦敖
Come watch this video.
过来看这个视频
Fu!
老付
This needle of yours
你这指针都
is already... off track.
都开始 你这玩意 转弯了
Where is it pointing at?
咱们指哪啊这
We could've had some more time
本来可以不用那么快
before playing the strongest opponent.
就遇见大魔王的
No need to look at the points table anymore.
积分表也不用看了
Yongchuan Hengjiu will surely defeat all their opponents
永川恒久肯定会击败所有对手
and advance as the first in the group.
以小组第一出线了
But yesterday, didn't you say there was still hope?
可你昨天不还说有希望
Given our players' state now, they might even
以他们现在的状态啊
have problems coordinating with each other in today's match.
今天比赛配合都会成问题
That said, Yongchuan Hengjiu is the strongest opponent
不过永川恒久是我们目前阶段
we can meet in the current stage.
能遇到最强的对手
Even if we lose simply because they're better,
就算因为实力差距而输了
at least our players get to enjoy the game itself.
他们也能够享受比赛本身
So, why not take a positive attitude
那为什么不能期待一场
to embracing a meaningful defeat,
有意义的失利呢
Ms. Lin?
小林老师
The bus is here.
车到了
Get on it, guys.
上车吧
-Okay. -Coming right up.
好好来了来了
Let's go.
走了
Pretty fancy, isn't it?
这也太豪华了吧
So posh.
这也太豪华了
Even the stadium hosting the game between us
踢永川恒久
and Yongchuan Hengjiu is different.
连赛场都变得不一样啦
What a fancy lounge.
这休息室也太高级了
I'm even more nervous now.
我更紧张了
When will the football field
咱们学校的足球场
in our school have facilities like these?
什么时候能有这样的配置
Hello, miss.
姐姐你好
My name is Qin Qiechu.
我叫秦且初
Hello.
你好
Coach!
教练
Coach Winfred,
温弗里德教练
I finally get to see you.
终于见到你了教练
I've always been a huge fan of yours.
我一直是你的超级粉丝
Why did you abandon our team?
你为什么对我们始乱终弃啊
So, this boy is...
所以他就是
Yes.
是
He is Qin Qiechu from Yongchuan Hengjiu.
他就是永川恒久的秦且初
You actually know who I am, Coach!
你还认识我啊教练
I'm so touched.
太感动了
Previously, you said you'd coach our team,
你之前说要来带我们队
but you didn't.
结果没来
After coaching them through this match,
那你这次带完他们之后
will you join our team?
能来我们队了吗
Bro,
兄弟
don't you think you're rude,
多冒昧啊
for calling another team's coach "Coach"?
管别人教练叫教练
You're Qin Ao!
秦敖啊
I love the way you penetrate into the box!
我喜欢你的禁区突破
Will you give me an autograph?
你给我签个名吧
Just sign your name right here.
就就就就这
Here, huh?
签这啊
T-To be honest,
说 说实话
if you become a star player in the future,
你以后要是当明星球员的话
such handwriting won't do.
这样的字可不行
A star player?
明星球员
Me?
我
You're Fu Xinshu, right?
付新书是吧
You work with Chen Jianghe in a quite interesting way.
你和陈江河的配合挺有意思
Thanks.
谢谢
Hello! Hello.
你好 你好
Qi Liang! Nice to meet you.
祁亮 你好你好
And you're Feng Suo, right?
冯锁是吧
You're quite a solid player.
你蛮稳的
Well...
那个
I-I have to go now,
我我得走了
or my captain will scold me.
队长该骂我了
S-See you later then.
那 那咱们待会见
See you!
待会见
Bye!
拜拜 拜拜
Guys,
兄弟们
Qin Qiechu is quite a people person, isn't he?
这秦且初有点太自来熟了吧
He knows us so well.
他这么了解我们
I have a bad feeling about it.
我有一种不祥的预感
Stop it.
停停停
Keep your feelings to yourself.
你别在这预感了啊
The game hasn't started yet.
这还没踢呢
No more pessimistic talk like that.
说什么丧气话
We won't know what they've got until we fight them.
啥水平也得踢过才知道啊
That's right.
对啊
Plus, the fact that our opponent
而且对手重视我们
takes us seriously means we're not half bad.
说明我们实力也不弱嘛
Exactly.
就是
Alright. It's time to get ready.
行了该准备了
Go get changed now.
都去换衣服吧
-Okay. -Got it.
好 行行行
-Let's go. -Time to get changed.
走走 换衣服
Everyone in the audience, welcome to the Youth Super League live match.
各位观众朋友青超联赛比赛现场
Today, the match will be held
本场对阵的队伍是
between Yongchuan Hengjiu and Hongjing No. 8 High School.
永川恒久队对宏景八中队
I believe you're all familiar with Yongchuan Hengjiu.
关于永川恒久相信大家很熟悉
It's the reigning five-time champion of the Youth Super League.
他是青超联赛五连冠的霸主
Joined by star players like No. 10, Qin Qiechu,
阵中拥有十号秦且初
and No. 7, Fang Sulun, it's fair to say
七号方苏伦等明星级球员
this team is the undisputed king of the pitch.
堪称赛场的王者之师
Most football fans
球迷普遍认为
believe that no one can defeat
在本届比赛中
this team in the ongoing tournament.
没有人能够战胜他们
On the other hand,
而宏景八中
for their classic free-kick strategy in the match
因与禹州银象的一战
against Yuzhou Yinxiang, Hongjing No. 8 High School
经典任意球战术
is hailed as the dark horse of this tournament.
被誉为本届黑马
Now, the dark horse has stepped onto the king's territory.
如今黑马踏上了王者的领地
Who will emerge victorious?
到底鹿死谁手
Let's see what will unfold before our eyes.
让我们拭目以待
The two teams' captains
双方队长
are exchanging pennants.
交换队旗
The pre-match coin toss is complete.
赛前掷币选边完成
The game is about to start.
比赛即将开始
Yongchuan Hengjiu!
永川恒久
-We've got this!
加油
Hongjing No. 8 High School!
宏景八中
-Go for it! -You've got this!
加油 加油 加油
Right from the kickoff,
比赛刚一开始
Hengjiu has shown dominant control over the pitch,
恒久就展现出了强大的控场能力
and is suppressing Hongjing in the midfield.
在中场压制住了宏景
Their 4-3-3 Formation
他们的这套四三三踢法
is working pretty smoothly,
运转非常流畅
with seamless coordination.
配合默契
Hengjiu's captain, Player No. 7, Fang Sulun, is dribbling
恒久队的队长 七号方苏伦
past the opponent's defense.
带球突破
-Defense! -He sold the opposing defenders
一个虚晃动作
-with a feint. -Defense!
过掉防守队员之后
Then he passes the ball to a midfielder.
把球传给了中路
The latter,
中路队员
without stopping the ball,
没有停球
passes it right back to Fang Sulun.
再次给到了方苏伦
-No. 10 bursts through the right flank. -Qin Ao, to the right!
右侧的高速突破
He's about to enter the box!
马上就要进入到禁区
This kick looks like both a pass and a shoot.
这一脚似传似射
Feng Suo fails to catch the ball.
冯锁没能拿到皮球
No. 10 comes up and shoots again.
跟进的十号补射
It's a goal!
应声入网
Qin Qiechu
秦且初
scored a goal right after the game started.
比赛刚刚开场
One to zero!
一比零
Bravo! Well done!
好 好样的
Yongchuan Hengjiu is now taking the lead.
永川恒久先声夺人
As expected of Qin Qiechu, a star player of Hengjiu,
秦且初不愧是恒久的种子选手
he has put on a brilliant performance.
果然表现惊人
Move!
走
In less than five minutes after the game started,
比赛才刚刚开始不到五分钟
Yongchuan Hengjiu got a grip of the match's pace
永川恒久掌控着比赛的节奏
and scored the first goal.
先拔头筹
Now, for Hongjing,
对于宏景八中来说
the priority
现在最需要做的是
is to steady themselves.
稳住阵脚
-After all, there's still plenty of time. -Keep your composure, guys!
毕竟 比赛的时间还非常充裕
They still stand a chance of tying
还是有机会追平
or even surpassing their opponent.
甚至是反超的
Hongjing is trying to steady the pace through passing,
宏景八中试图通过传球稳住节奏
while seeking a chance to attack.
寻找进攻的机会
But Hengjiu is pressing aggressively on the pitch.
但恒久在场上的逼抢非常的凶狠
Such intense pressing
这种压迫式的打法
is giving Hongjing a very hard time.
让宏景非常难受
Now, the ball is with Hongjing's captain,
现在宏景八中拿球的是
Player No. 10, Fu Xinshu.
场上队长十号付新书
That through ball is intercepted!
直塞球的机会被抢断了
They're even well aware of Fu Xinshu's
他们连付新书的传球习惯
passing patterns.
都那么清楚
Hengjiu disrupts the pass and gets the ball.
恒久队先一步抢断了皮球
Now, the ball is with...
现在拿球的是
Player No. 10 of Hengjiu, Qin Qiechu.
恒久队的十号秦且初
With excellent skills, he has dribbled past
通过个人能力
several opposing players in a row.
连续过人
Facing the defense being put up by Hongjing,
面对宏景回防的队员
a teammate of his quickly breaks through from the right.
这边右侧有队友高速插上
You want to pass the ball? Not a chance!
想传球 门都没有
Qin Qiechu doesn't
秦且初
pass the ball to the right flank,
没有传给右边
but to the midfield with a backheel.
脚后跟给到了中路
A shoot!
打门
Here comes one more goal!
球又进了
Good anticipation, but we prepared two plans.
预判不错 可惜我们有两套方案
Yongchuan is showing
永川的配合度
much better teamwork than Hongjing!
远远高于宏景八中啊
That attack
这一次进攻
was a textbook example of teamwork.
简直是教科书般的配合
Yongchuan Hengjiu
永川恒久
just scored another goal.
再拿一分
Now, it's 2-0 on the field.
场上比分 二比零
Conceding two goal consecutively soon after the game started
比赛刚刚开始 就被连入两球
might shake
宏景八中的球员
the mentality
在场上的心态
of Hongjing's players.
可能会受到影响
Hengjiu's players are too agile.
恒久太灵活了
Can't believe no one on our team fills the gap.
我们居然无人填补位移
Time is pressing.
来不及了
I'll do that then!
我来
Player No. 11 of Hongjing, Wen Chengye,
宏景的十一号文成业
seems to have left his position in defense
好像离开了自己的防守位置
for the attacking half, fighting for the ball.
开始前场围抢
Is it a new strategy of Hongjing's?
这是宏景新的战略吗
Wen Chengye left his defensive zone.
文成业离开了自己的防区
Wen Chengye, what are you doing?
文成业你干嘛
Not only did he fail to steal the ball,
非但没有抢下球
but he also occupied the same position
反而和回防的队友
with a teammate tracking back,
重叠了自己的位置
causing a gap in the defense.
造成了防守空挡
Wen Chengye,
文成业
where are you going?
你去哪
That defensive error shouldn't have
这完全是一次不必要的
happened.
防守失误
Wen Chengye
文成业
-is marking Qin Qiechu one-on-one again. -Bring it on.
再次个人盯防秦且初 来啊
Qin Qiechu seizes the chance
秦且初 抓住机会
to break through.
形成突破
He then passes the ball to his captain, Player No. 7,
传球给到了队长七号
Fang Sulun, who volleys hard!
方苏伦 大脚抽射
The ball hits a defender's leg,
球打在了后卫的腿上
deflects, and finds the net!
折射入网
Three to zero!
三比零
You alone can't turn the tables.
靠你一个人是不行的
Wen Chengye, what was that mess about?
文成业 在乱踢什么
Isn't the game a mess already?
现在还不够乱吗
Hongjing's No. 11 is a real headache.
这十一号挺难缠的呀
It's okay. Just try to avoid him.
没事 先尽量避开他
Yongchuan Hengjiu's passing is rather smooth.
永川恒久的传控行云流水
After scoring the third goal,
现在三比零之后
they've completely taken control of the pace on the field,
他们完全掌握了场上的节奏
and are bombarding
对着宏景八中的球门
Hongjing's goal.
是狂轰乱炸
Another link-up play in a small area.
又是局部的小配合
Then a long shot from outside the box.
禁区外缘的远射
Hongjing's defense is almost collapsing.
宏景八中的防线近乎崩溃
This time, a penetration through the midfield.
这一次是中路的直插
The ball goes to the left flank.
把球给到了左边
The player gently slots it home with his right foot.
右脚轻轻推射
Four to zero!
四比零啦
Yongchuan Hengjiu extended their lead again
永川恒久通过连续地施压
with relentless pressing.
再度扩大了比分
How could this happen?
怎么会这样
This happens
当天时地利人和
when all the conditions
都不站在我们这边的时候
are against us.
结果就是这样
Yu Ming pulled
俞明
and gave away a foul.
拉人犯规
-The referee showed him a yellow card. -No. 5, that was a foul.
裁判向五号俞明出示了黄牌
Hengjiu Team gets a free kick in the final third.
恒久队 前场定位球的机会
-It's okay. -Come here!
没事 没事 快来吧
-No biggie. -Form a wall.
没事 人墙 人墙
-All is fine. -It's okay.
没事
A free kick in a good position around the box.
前场位置不错的定位球
Will Hongjing keep this one out?
宏景能不能守住
Will Hengjiu further widen the gap by scoring one more goal?
恒久会不会进一步扩大场上比分
Lu, stay on him.
小鹿 压死他
The ball!
球
Yongchuan Hengjiu
永川恒久
actually adopted Hongjing's tactic
竟然复刻了上一场
on free kicks from the previous match!
宏景队的任意球战术
Player No. 19 in the offside position
在越位位置的
didn't take the ball.
十九号没有拿球
Instead, he let it slip through
而是轻轻一露
to Player No. 7, his captain,
由七号队长
Five to zero!
五比零
-It's a huge blow to Hongjing's morale. -Put in more effort!
这是对宏景的心理暴击啊
You've got this!
加油
Run forward!
往前跑
Qin Ao!
秦敖
-There's a good chance! -A good chance!
好机会
Pass it back!
回去
-Qin Ao! -Over here!
秦敖 这边 好
This is a great opportunity!
好机会
We can't lose one more score.
不能再丢球了
We can see now
我们看到
Player No. 11 of Hongjing, Wen Chengye,
宏景的十一号文成业
is still pressing hard non-stop in the middle and attacking thirds.
还在中前场不断地进行逼抢
Unfortunately, he's just running in an extensive area
可惜这种覆盖范围极大的跑动啊
without a clear target.
缺乏明确的针对性
Player No. 11 of Hongjing stole the ball
宏景十一号完成了抢断
by fooling Qin Qiechu with a fake.
假动作晃过了秦且初
He's now dribbling the ball forward.
继续带球推进
Hengjiu is in hot pursuit of him.
恒久队是紧追不舍
Both sides are battling fiercely for the ball in the midfield.
双方在中场展开了激烈的拼抢
Such a shame.
太可惜了
Player No. 11 of Hongjing fell.
宏景十一号球员
-Are you okay? -Although he has outstanding skills,
虽然个人能力突出
football requires teamwork after all.
但是足球终归是团队的游戏
Without team support on the field,
在场上没有队友的配合
individual brilliance amounts to nothing.
一个人只能是处处碰壁
Wen Chengye, what are you so arrogant about?
文成业你狂什么啊
Why put on airs?
你装什么呢
Enough, Qin Ao.
好了秦敖
I'm mad at him. What were you doing?
我不服你干嘛
Moving from the defensive half to the midfield,
从后场踢到中场
serving as a midfielder to a forward, huh?
中场踢到前锋是吧
Play or get off the pitch.
能踢踢
Do you even know how to pass?
会传球吗
Alright, stop it.
好了好了
They're having a mental breakdown.
他们的心态已经崩了
So is Wen Chengye.
文成业其实也崩了
But at least he's clear-minded.
但起码思路是清楚的
Yes. At least he's still trying.
是的 至少他还在努力
But it won't be of help.
但没用了
Wen Chengye has absolutely
文成业
no intention to cooperate with his teammates,
完全没有要配合队友的意愿
who have no idea what he's attempting to do.
其他队友也理解不了他的意图
What's there to do then?
那怎么办
The first half is coming to an end.
上半场比赛即将结束
The score has reached a shocking
比分来到了触目惊心的
7-0.
七比零
Hongjing completely fell apart
宏景八中在对手的冲击下
under the opponent's onslaught.
完全崩溃
This seems like the end of the first half,
看似是上半场比赛结束
yet the whole game is practically over.
但全场比赛其实早就结束了
Wen Chengye,
文成业
why did you quit your position?
你为什么要放弃自己的位置
If it weren't for you,
要不是因为你
would we have lost these many goals?
我们能被踢这么多球吗
What do you know?
你懂个什么
Who are you to blame me?
好意思说我
Qin Ao, did you even see everyone's position on the pitch?
秦敖 你看过场上的位置吗
Didn't you
别人拦你
know to run when others blocked you?
你不会跑吗
You were just standing there still.
和个木头一样杵在那
Say it again, I dare you!
再说一次
Fine, might as well speak my mind.
说就说了
You guys
你们这帮人
turn into wimps when you play against a strong team.
一踢强队就软得和豆腐一样
You collapse at the slightest attack.
一碰就散架
What?
怎么
Too embarrassed to admit how you performed?
有脸踢没脸说啊
Boss.
老大
Seems like you're not exhausted yet.
看来你们还有力气
Wen Chengye, I'm telling you,
文成业 我告诉你
if Coach weren't here today,
今天要不是教练在
I would beat you up
我准打你个满脸开花
to fix that foul mouth of yours.
治治你这张臭嘴
If you want a fight so badly,
你要这么想打
let's withdraw from the game,
干脆我们就弃赛
so you can brawl till there's blood!
打到头破血流为止
Otherwise, save all your energy and anger
要么就把你们的力气怒气都留着
for the opponent.
冲对方球队使
Coach Wang is right.
教练说的没错
The first half just ended.
现在只是刚上半场结束
The second half hasn't yet started.
下半场都还没开始呢
Everything is possible.
一切都没有定数
But falling apart right now
但倒在这里
means we've already lost.
就一定是输了
Will you accept that?
你们甘心吗
Of course not!
当然不甘心
Alright. Keep hydrated.
好了 大家该喝水喝水
Get some rest.
该休息休息
Conserve your energy.
保存体力
Prepare to give it your al in the second half.
准备全力冲刺下半场
Wen Chengye.
文成业
If you can't take it anymore,
你要坚持不下去的话
quit the second half.
下半场就别上了
I'm doing fine.
我没事
Wen Chengye,
文成业
use this medicine spray.
拿瓶药去喷喷
Taking the lead with seven scores,
恒久带着七颗球的领先优势
Hengjiu is on the pitch for the second half.
开始了下半场比赛
The relentless pressing in the first half
上半场的连续拼抢
has pushed Wen Chengye's stamina
让文成业的体能
almost to its limit.
近乎来到了极限
The second half has just begun,
下半场比赛刚刚开始
yet he is already physically drained.
他的体能已经见底
-If one wants to crash and burn, let him. -A forward of Yongchuan clearly
永川前锋显然注意到了这一点
noticed that and stole the ball from him.
从他脚下把球给断走了
The physical dropoff
体能的下降
causes Wen Chengye's technical movements
让文成业的技术动作
to break down badly.
出现了严重变形
What Wen Chengye said...
文成业那句话
Actually made a point.
不无道理
Their strength has improved a lot,
他们的实力已经提升很多了
and they have tactics in mind.
心里也有战术
But once they encounter a super strong opponent,
只是遇到超强队
they lose the ability to think quickly and analytically.
就失去了快速思辨的能力
We've already lost, haven't we?
我们已经输了对吧
Do you mind it a lot?
你很介意
There are ups and downs in life.
人生都有起起落落的
The same goes for a match.
更何况是比赛呢
It's just...
只是
I'm a bit reluctant to accept the result.
只是我有点不太甘心
On the pitch, things are constantly changing.
球场嘛 总是千变万化
A pre-planned formation doesn't always work.
预定好的阵容不会总是有效
In the face of sheer strength,
在绝对实力面前
all tactics are futile.
一切战术都是没有用的
Before surpassing Yongchuan Hengjiu,
他们距离超越永川恒久
our players still have a long way to go.
还有很长一段路要走
What you're saying
你这么说
sounds a bit fatalistic.
倒像是有点宿命论了
That's not what I mean.
我不是那意思
On the contrary,
相反
I respect our players' hard work.
我很尊重他们的努力
However, football is a team sport.
只是足球是团队运动
Now, there's already little teamwork left in them.
他们现在已经没有配合了
The players of Hongjing are having trouble coordinating
宏景队在后场的配合
with each other in the defensive half.
出现了一些问题
The team's execution and cohesion are both declining.
球队的执行力和凝聚力都在下降
Yongchuan Hengjiu just scored another goal,
永川恒久再下一城
extending their lead to 9-0.
比分扩大到了九比零
Hengjiu's on a great momentum,
恒久越踢越顺
while Hongjing's defensive formation
而宏景八中的防守阵型
has completely fallen apart.
已经完全脱节了
Yongchuan Hengjiu launches a long pass again as a counterattack.
永川恒久再次发动长传反击
-Let me take this! -Hongjing's No. 10, Fu Xinshu, and No. 11,
宏景十号付新书与十一号文成业
Wen Chengye, sprint at the same time.
同时冲刺
The two of them collide,
两人撞在了一起
but neither can touch the ball!
却都没能碰到球
An opportunity opens for Hengjiu.
恒久队的机会
They scores another goal!
再下一城
Bravo!
好样的
Boys,
小伙子们
-Fu!
老付 老付
Look, there was a foul.
你看 这都犯规了啊
-Are you okay, Fu?
老付 没事吧 老付
-Hongjing's No. 10 appears badly injured. -Is it the ankle?
宏景十号好像撞得很严重
-Medics have entered the pitch. -Fu Xinshu!
医护人员已经进场 付新书
They're quickly attending to the player.
在迅速处理球员的伤势
-Are you okay? -The right foot, huh?
没事吧
My foot...
我的脚
Hold still.
别动啊
Don't move.
别乱动
-Qin! -Qin Ao!
老秦 秦敖
-You did it on purpose, didn’t you?
文成业你故意的是吧
Talk later. The game's still on.
回去再说 踢球呢
Qin Ao,
秦敖
don't be like this.
你别这样
Right, I did that on purpose.
我就是故意的
-So what? -Qin Ao!
怎么了 秦敖
Apologize,
道歉
right now!
就现在
You're on a football field.
这是球场
All of you, shut up!
都闭嘴
Coach of Hongjing,
白队的教练员
can the team captain continue with the game?
你的队长还能继续比赛吗
Coach, I'm feeling much better after the ice spray.
教练我刚冰喷之后感觉好多了
I can continue with the game.
我还可以继续踢的
-Don't move. -Stay still.
你先别动
For this match,
本场比赛
the injured player Fu Xinshu is leaving the field.
受伤球员付新书会离场
The rest of the players will finish the game.
其余人会踢完全场比赛
will finish the game!
其余人踢完 全场比赛
Alright, let's go.
好啦 走吧
Go.
走
Be careful.
小心啊
Slowly.
慢点
Pass it to me!
给我
After what you did to Fu,
你害了老付还不够
you want me to pass the ball to you now?
现在还想让我传给你
In your dreams!
做梦
Ten players against eleven.
十打十一
Trailing by ten goals.
落后十个球
I've never seen a game
在我的职业生涯当中
like this in my entire career.
我从未见到过这样的比赛
The game is over.
全场比赛结束
The final score is 11-0.
最终的比分定格在十一比零
Yongchuan Hengjiu crushed Hongjing No. 8 High School!
永川恒久狂胜宏景八中